Anil Pise

Software Engineer, Ph.D*.(Computer Science)

280 Pretoria Avenue Randburg Johannesburg, SA № 0676775593 ⋈ anil.pise7@gmail.com



I am a PhD student at the School of computer science and applied mathematics at the University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg with my major research interest in deep learning and machine learning and their application to e-learning. I have working experience in the computer engineering industry. I have published 5 international conference papers and 1 national level journal paper. Moreover, I am currently working on Legacy Data Migration Project of WITS University.

Education

2016–2019 University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, Ph.D., Computer Science, Deep Learning.

2013–2015 Patel Institute of Technology Bhopal, M-Tech, Computer Science, Facial Expression Recognition.

2014–2014 MindScripts Technology Training Solutions Pune, Diploma In Software Software Testing, India.

2005–2010 SVERI Pandharpur Solapur University, BE, Computer Science and Engineering, India.

Experience

2019-Present Intern, IT SERVICE MANAGEMENT, University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg,

Project title: Legacy Data Migration Project

IT SERVICE MANAGEMENT

- Promote and support the deployment of Service Management processes to all groups interacting with Problem Management, Change Management and Incident Management.
- Effectively execute and drive continuous improvement for IT Change Management.
- Secondary support for Configuration Management, Vendor Management, Procurement, Asset and Service Level Management.
- Produce activities and workflow documentation for Change, Incident and Problem Management.
- Manage small projects related to ITSM delivery improvement for WITS University.
- Weekly metrics reporting to management and collection of University staff's status reports.
- Create, maintain and follow policies to improve internal services.
- Establishes policy, procedures, and standards to ensure consistent, high quality delivery of service management.
- Provide 24x7 Tier 1 support for all High Priority Incidents.
- Develops asset and configuration management standards, plans and procedures.
- Metrics management, reporting and effective management of formal Post analysis meeting.
- Co-ordination with upstream providers for internet routing and network congestion related issues.
- Demonstrated experience in ITSM/ITIL practice in defining, implementing and managing various ITIL processes including but not limited to: Change Management, Incident Management, Problem Management, Release Management, Configuration Management, Asset Management, Knowledge, Service Catalog, Service Level Management, Availability Management, and Capacity Management.

2016–2019 **Research Scholar**, Enhancement of e-learning platform, Research Focusing on deep learning and relational reasoning, Project title: Facial Emotion Recognition Using Tube Temporal Relational Network.

Research and Technology Management

- Installation, configuration, integration, and management of Deep Learning system architectures, clusters, git hub repositories and system interfaces.
- Team player who can also be independent, prioritize work and thrives in a fast-paced dynamic environment.
- Drive and motivation for career development and open to taking on challenges.
- Strong mathematical fundamentals, including linear algebra and numerical methods.
- Working directly with key application developers to understand the current and future problems they are solving, creating and optimizing core parallel algorithms and data structures to provide the best solutions using GPUs, through both library development and direct contribution to the applications of Deep Learning.
- Collaborating closely with the architecture, research, libraries, packages, tools, and system software teams at NVIDIA
 to influence the design of next-generation architectures, software platforms, and programming models, including by
 investigating impact on application performance and developer productivity.
- Actively participate in challenging software and hardware research projects focused at applying combination of Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing and Knowledge Representation pipelines to design, analysis and engineering workflows for real world problems.
 - 2012–2016 **Teaching-(Assistant Professor)**, Sinhgad Institute of Technology Lonavala Pune India, Teaching, Distributed Operating System, Computer Networks, Data Structure.
 - 2010–2012 **Teaching-(Lecturer)**, Bhivarabai Sawant College of Engineering and Research Narhe Pune India, Teaching, Fundamental Programming Languages, STLD.

Conferences/Workshops

- 1-Actively participated in AI and ML Deep Dive with AWS conference organised at Amazon Web Services South Africa.
- 2-Actively participated in Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals Big Data and Machine Learning conference organised at Google South Africa.
- 3-Actively participated in Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals Conference organised at Google South Africa.
- 4-Actively participated in Deep Learning Indaba-X-2019 International Workshop organised by University of Kwazulu-Natal Durban.
- 5-Actively participated in Deep Learning Indaba-2017 International Workshop organised by University of the Witwatersrand.
- 6-Actively participated in IIT BOMBAY ORGANISED 2-WEEK ISTE WORKSHOP on Software Development Techniques for Teachers of Engineering and Science Institutes Under the National Mission on Education through ICT (MHRD, Govt. of India).
- 7-Actively participated in IIT BOMBAY ORGANISED 2-DAY ISTE WORKSHOP on Writing Effective Conference Papers-Under the National Mission on Education through ICT (MHRD, Govt. of India).
- 8-Actively participated in IIT BOMBAY ORGANISED 2-WEEK ISTE WORKSHOP on Introduction to Research Methodologies-Under the National Mission on Education through ICT (MHRD, Govt. of India).
- 9-Actively participated in 2-DAYS NATIONAL CONFERENCE ON BUILDING RICH WEB APPLICATIONS USING .NET.
- 10-Actively participated in 2-DAYS STATE LEVEL WORKSHOP ON MATLAB-SIM POWER SYSTEM.
- 11-Actively participated in 1-DAY STATE LEVEL WORKSHOP ON MATLAB-SIM and Its Applications.

Skills

- 5+ years of related experience.
- In depth knowledge of Deep Learning systems application architectures using Python.
- Contribution to research communities and efforts, including publishing papers at conferences.
- Experience working with modern Deep Learning software architecture and application.
- Drive and motivation for career development and open to taking on challenges.
- Experience with Convolution Neural Networks and toolkits including CAFFE, cuda-convnet, and others.

— INTERESTS/Hobbies

- 1. Reading and Writing Marathi Drama Scripts.
- 2. Organizes and Conduct Stress Management Seminar through SAHAJAYOGA meditation.

REFERENCES

- 1. Dr.Hima Vadapalli (Senior Lecturer at University of the Witwatersrand).
- 2. Mr. Yashin Brijmohan (Executive Dean at Monash University South Africa).
- 3. Emman Raj Munduthara (PMP, MBA) (ICT Project Manager at Accenture).
- 4. Radhika Kapshikar (Senior Software Developer at Multichoice).